ABID ALI ELECTRICAL POWER ENGINEER

abidali8990@gmail.com Hyderabad, Sindh - Pakistan +92310-8518990

PROFILE

Graduated engineer in training, offering extensive knowledge power systems analysis, operations, protection and control and also have depth knowledge in power electronics, focused on putting my research, university studies and knowledge to practical, applied use in Power Systems Engineering. To utilize my technical skills for achieving the targets and best performance in esteemed organization.

SKILLS

Design Suite Software Protues

Diagramming and Vector Visio

Graphics Application

PCB Designing Software Altium, OrCAD

Power Electronics Simulation Software **PSIM**

Programming C/C++

Software Arduino, MS Office, MATLAB

EXPERIENCE

Islamabad Electric Supply Company

Jul 2017 - Aug 2017

Internship

During internship I observed the working of different electrical components such as transformer, relay, isolators etc. I also perform following activities

- Schematic Drawing of Grid Station Equipment.
- Single Line Diagram of Grid Station.
- Detail Operation of Grid Station Equipments.

SPECIAL PROJECTS

High Current Switching Mode Power Supply	Sep 2017 - Jun 2018
Buck Converter	May 2017 - Jun 2017
Short/Medium Transmission Line Module	Oct 2016 - Jan 2017

EDUCATION

SSC, Science, Grade: A

COMSATS University Isalamabad B.Sc, Electric (Power) Engineering, CGPA: 2.95/4.0	2014 - 2018
Ustad Bukhari Govt. Degree College Dadu F.Sc, Pre-Engineering, Grade: B	2001 - 2014
The Citizen Foundation School Johi	2010 - 2012

HONORS

3rd Position in 5th Semester Jan 2017

COMSATS University Islamabad

LANGUAGES

Expert Balochi

Practitioner English, Urdu, Sindhi

SOCIAL

https://www.facebook.com/ABIDBALOCH8990

https://www.linkedin.com/in/abid-ali-7b984b146/